Contact

ali.sarioz@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/alisarioz-84261052 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Bilgi Güvenliği Yönetimi Sorun Giderme Paydaş Yönetimi

Ali Sarioz

IT Manager at Tchibo Türkiye

Istanbul, Istanbul, Türkiye

Summary

A multi-skilled IT executive with good all-round supervisory and technical expertise. Very capable with a proven ability to ensure the smooth running of ICT systems and to provide IT services that will improve the efficiency and performance of a company.

Experience

Tchibo Türkiye Information Technology Manager June 2019 - Present (5 years 10 months) Istanbul, Turkey

Managing IT Budget

Managing Third-party relations and agreements

Managing outsourced developer and consultant teams

Working with Global Helpdesk and Managing Local On-Site Support team to ensure incidents/ problems are resolved within SLA

Managing license agreements

I have managing network and security services including Lan/WAN technologies, Firewall, DLP, and Log Management with Global Network Team Managing timely upgrade and build of Computers / Workstations Standard Operating Procedures to meet Global IT Requirements.

I have managing Server, Storage, Backup, and Recovery operations including virtualization platforms, hardware, and appropriate software solutions,

Managing Physical inventory of the IT Equipment

Supporting high-level stakeholders regarding technology

Managing procedures and processes according to regulative necessities.

ERP integration processes

Marketplace integration processes

KVKK and GDPR processes

Following to PCI DSS process

Business Continuity Coordinator

Fiba Perakende Grubu

IT Management Supervisor

October 2017 - June 2019 (1 year 9 months)

Istanbul, Turkey

- •Create and apply information security policies, procedures and systems for information security processes,
- •Responsibility of ISO 27001, KVKK and PCI-DSS compatibility,
- Detect and report information security issues
- Management of access controls
- Management and monitoring of log controls
- •Planning and conducting internal audits
- Management of Information Security Incidents
- •Data Loss Prevention & Practice Tests.
- •Recommended changes to improve systems and network configurations, and determined hardware and software
- •Coordinated with vendors and with company personnel in order to facilitate purchases.
- •Researched new technology and implemented it and recommended its implementation.
- •Disaster Recovery Plan and DRP Practice Tests.

Toyota Turkey

System & Network Security Expert

February 2015 - October 2017 (2 years 9 months)

Istanbul, Turkey

- Demonstrated leadership ability and industry expertise in IT Project
 Management. Success at achieving sophisticated
 technology goals on-time and on-budget. Proven ability to inspire, motivate
 and lead a team to produce quality work in the
 development of solutions.
- Planned, coordinated, and implemented network security measures in order to protect data, software, and hardware.
- Coordinated with vendors and with company personnel in order to facilitate purchases.
- Analyzing business needs to improve efficiency and to create new opportunities for the business.
- Researched new technology and implemented it and recommended its implementation.
- Recommended changes to improve systems and network configurations, and determined hardware and software
 requirements related to such changes.

- Data Loss Prevention & Practice Tests.
- ISO 27001 preperations and process management & follow up.
- Disaster Recovery Plan and DRP Practice Tests.
- Monitored network performance in order to determine whether adjustments needed to be made, and to determine where changes will need to be made in the future.
- IT asset management with Financial Accounting Team

British American Tobacco Turkey 4 years 1 month

IT Technology Service Coordinator January 2013 - January 2015 (2 years 1 month) Istanbul, Turkey

- Managing a team of over 5 administrative & technical staff.
- Strengthening the IT infrastructure through to implementing new technologies.
- Performing routine audits of systems and software.
- Manage the IT budgets and expenditure on hardware and software.
- Developing & maintaining the company IT systems, software and databases.
- Recommending and implementing improvements and efficiencies.
- Analyzing business needs to improve efficiency and to create new opportunities for the business.
- Having excellent time management, confidentiality & communication skills.
- Having strong IT, commercial, planning and budgeting skills.
- Management of server software and associated backup routines.
- To evaluate, test, advise, train and support I.T. related projects.
- Procurement of IT hardware, software and maintenance products & services.
- Responsible for the recruitment and training of new staff.
- Writing documentation for ICT procedures, security and disaster recovery.
- Maintaining documentation of changes regarding users, functions & systems.
- Managing the internal & hosted network infrastructure including: firewalls, servers, switches and telephony.
- IT asset management with Financial Accounting Team.

Technology Service Coordinator January 2011 - January 2013 (2 years 1 month)

- Managing a team of over 5 administrative & technical staff. (HQ and Factory)
- Managed MPLS project containing 11 cities which resulted with %20 cost saving.

- Global Zscaler Integration Project.
- Cisco Telepresense VC project & implementation. Reduced travel and accommodation costs.
- IT Security penetration tests and security.
- APN Project implementation for field sales operations.
- Track and Trace project (EU Regulations track a product from factory to end user) . Infrastructure implementation and process management.
- Product Integrity and Traceability. It Infrastructure implementation.

British American Tobacco Turkey
IT Services & Network Administrator
January 2004 - January 2007 (3 years 1 month)
Istanbul

- Diagnose hardware and software problems, and replace defective components.
- Perform data backups and disaster recovery operations.
- Maintain and administer computer networks and related computing environments, including computer hardware, systems software, applications software, and all configurations.
- Plan, coordinate, and implement network security measures in order to protect data, software, and hardware.
- Operate master consoles in order to monitor the performance of computer systems and networks, and to coordinate computer network access and use.
- Perform routine network startup and shutdown procedures, and maintain control records.

Education

Ahmet Yesevi Üniversitesi

Master of Science - MS, Cyber Security · (August 2021 - September 2022)

Anadolu Üniversitesi

Bachelor's Degree, Business Administration and Management, General · (2010 - 2014)

Gloucestershire College

English Language · (2010)

Sakarya Üniversitesi

Associate's Degree, Endüstriyel Elektronik · (2003 - 2006)